Hey everyone, and thanks for jumping
back into the cryptoverse.
Today, we're going to talk about Bitcoin
as the month of July comes to an end. If
you guys like the content, make sure you
subscribe to the channel, give the video
a thumbs up, and check out the sale on
Into the Cryptoverse Premium at
intothecryptoverse.com.
As a reminder, the ITC conference is
coming
November 20th through the 22nd
in Miami. So, make sure you guys get
your ticket. We're going to be raising
the prices here in just a few weeks.
Also, note that it does include food at
the conference, and we're even going to
have one of the annual ITC parties. So,
if you haven't been able to make one of
those, hopefully I will see you there.
Link is in the description below.
Let's go ahead and jump in. So, this
July
looks like basically every other midterm
year July in recent history for Bitcoin.
If you look at monthly returns in July,
you can see so far in 2026, up about 10
and 1/2% not bad.
2022 was up almost 20%.
2018 almost up 38%. So,
July
in midterm years often acts as some
relief.
Normally,
it is the month that provides the relief
after you get a pretty big drop going
into June, late June, early July.
If you're not familiar, you can pretty
clearly see
2022 Bitcoin dropped into June and then
found a low,
and then had it sort of this
brief countertrend rally into about
mid-August. Did not quite make it to the
bear market resistance band before
coming back down.
In 2018, we had that drop into June.
Then, we did make it to the bear market
resistance band before coming back down,
and we were still at that bear market
resistance band in like late July.
In 2014, it's a little bit different
because in 2014, the low was not in
June, it was actually in
October.
There was a low in June, but it was a it
was sort of a higher low, so it was a
lot stronger during that period. But
what you'll notice is every time you get
a low in June,
you get a rally on the other side of it
going into July, as you can see,
sometimes going into August, and then as
you get later into Q3,
that's when you start to see that window
of weakness come back. All right?
Now,
in 2018, which we have talked at length
about the similarities between 2026 and
2018, if you look at the year-to-date
RLI of Bitcoin in 2026 and overlay that
with 2018, you can see how it more or
less lines up, and starting in about a
day or two is when Bitcoin started to
show that window of weakness again. But
again, in 2022, it took a little bit
longer, right? Before that weakness came
back. So a lot of people have reached
out and they're like, "Well, is Bitcoin
going to reach the bear market
resistance band? Is it, you know, is is
the rally over now that we're basically
through July?"
The the true answer is that is that no
one knows. Like I can't with a clear
authoritarian voice say one way or
another whether Bitcoin's going to reach
the bear market resistance band and or
the 200-day moving average. Okay? I
mean, in 2022, we did not reach them
after the June low, right? And by the
time we reached it, the bear market
resistance band was all the way out in
November, and we didn't even get back up
to the 200-day moving average after the
April rejection. We didn't get back to
the 200-day moving average until January
of the following year.
If you look at 2018,
we did get back up there, right? We we
made it back up Well, not even quite. We
got to the bear market resistance band
in near the end of July, and then almost
to the 200-day moving average by late
July, early August, but we never
actually touched the 200-day moving
average.
From like, you know, early from like
April or so of 2018 all the way until
April of the following year.
So,
it's hard to say for sure whether we'll
tag it or not, but the point is is if
history is any indication,
the next window of weakness is going to
show up is going to start sometime in
the next 2 to 3 weeks.
In 2022,
it did not really start to show up again
until about mid-August.
In 2018, it showed up early August.
It's It's hard to know exactly the day I
which is going to occur, but I will say
this,
in 2023, Bitcoin started going down from
July,
and it corresponded
with the with the long end of the yield
curve going up, right? The 10-year yield
was heading higher during that time, as
you can see right here. The 10-year
yield started going up, and you'll know
that the 10-year yield is starting to
make that move once again. The bond The
bond market is starting to revolt. The
Fed's not raising rates, and if this
plays out
like either 2023 or 2022 or 2018 or
2014,
then you'd be looking at a correction
coming up in the latter part of Q3. So,
it made sense to say that look, we were
going to form a low by late June, early
July. We did. Countertrend rally in
July, check.
Could it extend a little bit into
August?
It could, but I would guess that we'll
see
um
Bitcoin come back down as we get later
on uh into the month of August, and and
notably September. What's remarkable is
when you look at the monthly returns of
Bitcoin in midterm years, July is often
green, but look at 2022, July was green
and then August, September red. 2018,
July was green, August, September red.
Even in 2014 when July was red, August
and September were still red.
So,
I'm not here to say that it you can't
see it go up. Even in 2022, Bitcoin
finished the month -15%, but it started
the month strong. So, this is one of
those things where it's hard to know the
exact day, but we are we're we're
readily approaching, I think, the next
window of weakness for Bitcoin. It
usually starts to present itself in the
month of August and September of midterm
years. So, we'll see if that comes to
pass,
um and, you know, if this just plays out
like every other prior bear market, then
we'd be looking at a low here in in just
a few months. If you go to the ROI from
the low chart, which we've talked about,
you know, a number of times on this
channel, and you go out low to low, you
can see that, you know, just a few more
months and we'll be kind of at that same
length of of prior bear markets. I would
encourage people, not financial advice,
but normally a DCA strategy is going to
work best rather than trying to time the
exact bottom. But, this is playing out
in a very familiar fashion as prior bear
markets have. And so, I'm hoping that by
around November or so,
we'll be either out of market cycle
bottom already or it'll be relatively
close to being in. So, if you want to
come join the discussions about that,
check out the first ITC conference
taking place this November in Miami. Get
your tickets down in the description
below or the pinned comment. Uh the
prices are going to go up here in just a
few weeks. So, thank you guys for tuning
in, subscribe, and I'll see you next
time. Bye.